Now...
wake up...
It's show time...
Come on...
Huh?
What is this place?
I'm Arl!
I'm a plump shorty who's always hungry!
I'm Pul!
I'm a slim beanpole who's a braggart!
Note: The word "nakama" means friend and comrade, but the word is being
mispronounced and Pino consequently mislearns the word
We're NakaMa who get along great!
Where is this?
Where, you ask?
This is the hometown of smiles!
Welcome to World Smile Land!
Smile?
You complete my fate
The world unwinds inside of me
The halo crawls away
You refill my place
Come and save me
Believe in me and drink the wine and take my hand and fill me up
Golo presents
Come and save me
meditation  girl smile
This is World Smile Land.
It's an amusement city that exists
to give our patrons an eternal smile.
Yep.
The whole city is a wonderful amusement park.
Which means the people of this
city can play and laugh year-round.
Of course, to make sure they keep smiling,
we come out with new animals and characters all the time.
Also, attractions and cast members that people get bored with
go bye-bye in a flash!
And this place...
Is where they get dumped!
That was a close call.
By the way, Miss, what's your name?
Why did you come here?
I was traveling with Vince and Re-l on the rabbit, but...
Vince?
Re-l?
You know them?
Not at all.
We're NakaMa who get along great!
I wonder if I got thrown away too.
I'm in trouble...
Trouble, trouble...
Mm, trouble...
I know!
When in trouble, ask!
All right!
We are in trouble right now too, actually.
It's so great that we're all in trouble at the same time!
What are we going to ask?
That's obvious!
We're going to ask the creator of our world's smiles:
Will B. Good!
You're better off not ad-libbing like that.
There's no time left for that, you know.
Oh, here's the mole.
Oh, here's the spy.
Ignoring me, are you?
Note: He's trying to make a pun from "mushi", which can means "bug" or "to ignore".
Oh, just 'cause I'm a bug...
Hey, listen to me!
Who're you?
Oops, this is the real reason I'm here.
Miss,
if you stick with these guys, you're not going to get anywhere.
Jeez, I've been looking all over for you.
I had no idea you'd wandered into a place like this.
Note: His name is a pun on the word for cricket (koorogi).
I'm Rogi the cricket.
Well, nice to meetcha.
I'm looking for Vince and Re-l.
That's what I thought!
You know them?
Of course!
You'll find out where they are if you come with me to Will B. Good.
Alrighty.
Let's go!
But...
Um... Like this...
Uhh...
Their... roles are over.
Never mind the nitty-gritty details!
Note: This refers to Akutagawa Ryuunosuke's famous work, "The Spider's Thread",
in which Buddha lowers a spider's thread into hell to save a sinner.
This is like spider's thread!
Hold on!
We lost the postcards, didn't we.
That's fine.
We've discovered that just asking isn't good enough.
So we're going to take action.
Actually, why are you guys coming with us?
We're going to Will B. Good.
Why?
To ask him why we were born.
Good would know, since he created us.
How idiotic.
You've changed your reason too.
But I guess you're gonna ignore me again anyway.
I'm sure there's a reason why we were born.
He has to tell us what it is.
A reason...
In any case,
you guys aren't a part of this deal.
Go home already.
We want to go too!
Want to!
Please take Arl and Pul too. Please?
That's why we should've left them behind.
I know.
Um...
I'm not trying to ask anything in return for taking them, but...
can you tell me one thing?
What?
Um...
What kind of person is this Mr. Vince?
He's nice to me.
So I love him.
And since Vince loves Re-l,
I love Re-l too.
Not that sort of thing... more like Mr. Vince's...
special traits?
Mm...
He's always being a wimp,
but sometimes he'll change in a flash and get big and strong!
Just as I thought.
And what is his Achilles' heel?
Hey!
Pino!
This way, this way!
Come take a look!
Dammit.
There's so little time left.
Super surprised!
Weren't you surprised?
It's good, Guest.
Doesn't it seem fun?
Good for you, Guest!
Totally!
Good, isn't it, Guests.
We're all NakaMa who get along great!
Geez.
Forget that. We need to go to Good quick...
Hey! You can't go outside!
So exciting!
Isn't it?
Right, right, right!
This is posted all over.
This is a notice that the end of everyone's world is near.
Well, not that it has anything to do with us.
Idiot!
You and I are all included in the "everyone"!
It's the end of the world!
Armageddon's coming soon!
Uh, are you ignoring me again?
I heard that it's a story that Good's
been writing while cooped up in his room.
Though it's not coming along at all.
Jeez.
Who cares?
Let's just go to Will...
I'm begging you guys.
You there.
Do all of you have a pass?
No.
Um...
Well, you can't ride for free!
Told ya.
Pino!
Run!
Get her!
Wait, stop!
Fun!
Give up!
Hey, look. That girl...
Get her-
She's great.
She's smiling...
but so naturally...
I've never seen anyone smile like that.
Not to mention...
Yeah.
She's not faking it.
Pino...
It stops here!
Wha?
Whaaa?
Pino!
No!
I don't need ad-libs in my world!
Pino was great.
Pino looked like she was having so much fun.
It was really fun.
I remember Papa taking me to a mall a long time ago.
Wow, you have a father even though you're a machine?
But we haven't been together for a long time.
That's so sad.
Do you want to see your father again?
No, I'm okay.
Why?
He's still your father, right?
But I'm with important NakaMa now.
So that's Vince...
And Re-l.
I hope we'll get to meet them.
Yeah.
What are you NakaMa going to do after meeting Good?
Hmm, well, the attraction we were living in is gone.
Oh, then I want to be a guest next!
Oh! I just thought of that too!
Jeez, your reason changed again.
I bet you're going to ignore me again too.
A guest?
If that happens...
We can smile forever.
Do you understand the trouble you're in?!
Note: The name is a pun on the word for a dog's bark (wan).
Here it is, Police Detective Wan.
Uh, let's see...
First, the small one over there.
Rogi, eh.
An autoreiv for scouting and surveillance.
And the duo over there, Arl and Pul...
Note: The Commedia dell'arte was a popular form of improv theater that began in
the 16th century and featured characters such as Arlecchino and Pulcinella.
You're both entertainment-type autoreivs
and cast members of Commedia dell'arte.
Here.
Commedia dell'arte was just shut down!
Then you should've been sent off to the trash bin already!
And the biggest problem, you,
aren't in any of our records, but...
I'm Pino.
Who are you?
I'm me!
Th-That's...
A-A natural smile!
Note: The name is a pun on the word for a cat's meow (nyaa).
C-C-Calm down, Officer Nyarrl.
But!
Th-That's a mighty natural smile you've got there.
A new function, right?
I got a soul after I met NakaMa like Vince and Re-l.
So when I'm having fun, I smile.
Smile for me!
You're dazzling!
Ugh!
There's no time for this!
Listen up, everyone!
You're stuck in the exposition stage in
the plot, and the story's going nowhere!
Forget it.
We're skipping the climax and jumping straight to the conclusion!
What?
Welcome.
Welcome to my world, World Smile Land.
Will B. Good!
Our creator!
Hi, my name is Will B. Good.
I created this to be a place where everyone can keep smiling.
But you know, that's actually harder than it looks.
Everyone can smile for a short while.
But the really hard part is to keep everyone smiling.
And do you know what?
Sometimes people laugh even when
they've been scared witless or have cried their eyes out.
To make perfect smiles,
you need tight control on things.
And that's why I made Smile Land.
Perfect smiles...
Smiles that should be made and protected...
Wonderful smiles that make the world happy...
Smiles that let people forget reality
and the terror that awaits until the last possible moment.
Yes...
The people of this city
play here from the day they're born until the day they die.
And they can meet the world's end, ignorant and happy.
Isn't that great?
Great, great!
Good, good.
Pino,
you want to see Vince and Re-l, don't you.
You know them?
Of course.
I know everything.
After all, I'm the creator.
But before that, can you tell me a tiny little something?
What is Vincent's - no, Ergo PROXY's - weakness?
Weird.
You said you know everything.
Can't you whisper it to me, like you would a secret?
I don't know.
Then do you not want to see them?
I do.
Then please tell me.
But I really don't know.
Then do you know anything?
Like, what he considers a treasure...
Come now... Remember...
G-Good...
A treasure...
to Vince...
I don't know!
Are you telling the truth?
It's true!
I see.
That's too bad.
Because if you had Vince's treasure right now...
I could grant you any wish...
You're lying.
Good, good...
Now then, look behind you.
Who are you?
What are you saying?
It's us.
Arl and Pul.
We asked him to make us into visitors.
I granted their wish.
You get it now, don't you?
I'll grant your wish next, Pino.
So, come...
Believe in me, the creator of this paradise of smiles...
Come...
Aren't those smiles kind of fake?
What?
Pino's smiles were so natural!
Our smiles are... sort of superficial...
Or shallow...
They don't have any substance.
Fake!
They're totally different from Pino's smiles.
Shut up!
How can you,
characters created by me, criticize me?
You're kidding me!
You guys will do as I say!
Getting in my way with your stupid ad-libs...!
Besides, what's all this about
wanting to know the reason you were born?
As if something like that exists!
You're all meaningless defects!
Geez! You worthless scum!
What?
So fun!
W-Wait, please.
There's no time... left...
Please, Pino.
Please tell Vince and Re-l not to come here.
Listen.
Vince will come here soon.
When PROXIES meet...
He and I will have to fight.
Really?
Yes.
And if that happens...
this place won't stay peaceful anymore.
Will... everyone die?
Yes...
That's why I interfered with your dreams
and tried to find out what Vince's weakness was from you.
But that failed.
Is this... a dream?
It's a dream... and yet not a dream.
Really?
Aren't you messing with us again?
No!
It's true!
Please believe me.
The world will come to an end soon anyway.
That's just fate.
But...
until then...
I want to spend the time quietly here, smiling.
I don't want to fight anymore.
Pino,
we're asking you too.
We want to keep smiling too.
Because you taught us what a natural smile is, so...
NakaMa...
I can hear the heartbeat of beginning.
Soon...
Huh?
Gone...
They're gone!
Maybe I did give them to him...
Vince!
Are you done charging up?
Um, Vince, can you bend down a little?
What is it?
You have it!
Are you still half asleep?
Look, we're starting to see lights up ahead.
There may be a city.
It'll be nice if we can restock some of our supplies,
but getting some rest will be nice enough.
City...?
Could it be...
No!
We mustn't go there!
Did you fry a circuit?
NO!
Don't be difficult.
I want to save the NakaMa!
"NakaMa"?
Please!
If we go there, something bad will happen.
I know it!
Nothing good will come of it.
Let's leave them alone!
Please, Vince?
Believe me.
All right then.
Vince!
Vincent!
In this way, Smile Land was saved by a girl.
Thank you, Smile Girl!
Thank you, Pino!
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
A familiar paradise of monotony...
The days of chance encounters are warm and familiar.
And...
meditation  sacred eye of the void
Goodbye, Vincent.